1. OPERATING SYSTEM – 
It is a system software that manages computer hardware, software resources and provide common services for computer program.
It manages computer memory and processes,as well as of its hardware and software.
Uses: Process, memory, file, device management, and security and user control.
OS has worked in 3 parts: Application, Shell, Kernel
					
			      	USERS
				      |
			          Application
			        	      |
			System Interface
				     |
			OPERATING SYSTEM (Windows, Ubuntu)
			                   |
			Computer Hardcore( CPU, MEMORY, DISK)  

2. Kernel -           
It directly interacts with the hardware. 
E.g. When we open any program -> request goes to kernel -> Kernel tells hardware what to do.


3. Shell  -			
Interface b/w User and kernel, through which user can communicate with OS.
User sends command to kernel -> Kernel executes command and send Output back to user.
					

4. Application -      
Sofware or program that userr directluy use. Application works by using shell and kernel.					


5. Linux -        
Linux is the Kernel that's why perform better than Windows. 
Open Source and community developed OS/Kernel for computers, servers, mainframes, mobiled devices. 
Written in C because C has faster program execution speed.
Popular Linux Distribution are Ubuntu, Fedora , Mint, Debian, CentOS etc.
